So today we are going to talk about the tools that you will need for wire jewelry making.
You will start with a pair of round nose pliers.
You will need a pair of flat nose pliers.
You will also of course need wire.
A towel so your beads don’t fly away.
Beads or findings and wire cutters.
Your round nose pliers are essential.
That’s what you are going to need to work with the wire, to bend the wire.
Also these are really cool because you can, they have got flat nose and round so it's kind of an all in one pair of pliers.
You can actually cut the wire with these.
These are a little hard to find but if you can find them I suggest it highly.
Your flat nose pliers you are going to use to flatten the wire, these you also have an option to wrap the wire.
Wire comes in varying sizes, gauges and types so we will go into that a little later.
Your beads are basically by your choice.
Whatever beads kind of call to you.
And then a pair of wire cutters, you want to get the most, the sharpest and best quality wire cutters as possible.
Finally your towel is going to keep from your beads flying all over the place and that’s your basic needs for wire making jewelry.